A Finding Aid to the Chester Beach Papers, 1846-1999, bulk circa 1900-1999, in the Archives of American Art AAA.beacches
Archives of American Art
- Photographs, circa 1885-circa 1960s; Series 10; 3.1 Linear feet Boxes 4-9, 11, 14
  - Artwork by Chester Beach (Box 4)
    - Sculpture, Unidentified, undated; 5 Folders (Box 5, Folder 1-5)
  - Artwork by Other Artists (Box 5)
    - Portraits of Chester Beach by G. Laurance Nelson and Natalie Beach McLaury, 1957-1958; 1908 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - People (Box 5)
    - Chester Beach, circa 1910-1938; circa 1885; undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Chester Beach Working in his Studio, 1932; circa 1909; (oversized material housed in Box 11) (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Chester Beach with his Sculpture, undated; circa 1966; circa 1899 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Chester Beach with Others, undated; circa 1910s (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Chester Beach with Family, circa 1915-1953; undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Beach Family (daughters Beata, Eleanor, and Natalie), 1928 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Places (Box 5)
    - Beach's Boyhood Home, San Francisco, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
      See: Box 11
    - Beach's Studios, New York City and Brewster, NY, circa 1960s; undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Brookgreen Gardens, Murrell's Inlet, SC, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Subjects - Nude Models, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Negatives - Artwork by Chester Beach (Box 5)
    - Walt Whitman (Hall of Fame for Great Americans), undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Negatives - People (Box 5)
    - Chester Beach (circa 1910; Gertrude Kasebier, photographer), undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
      copy negatives
    - Chester Beach (circa 1930), undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
      copy negative
  - Glass Plate Negatives - Sculpture by Chester Beach
    - Handwritten Glass Plate List for Box L, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Fountain Figure in Plaster, Studio, Box A, undated; 3 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Pan Sculpture, Box A, undated; 2 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - 'Breath of Pines' (Ivory), Box A, undated; 3 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - 'Spirit of the Woods' (Bronze), Box A, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Nathalie (Bust), Box A, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - George Maron (Bust), Studio, Box A, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Jonathan Thorne (Relief), Box A, undated; 1 Glass negatives (8 x 10) (Box 8)
    - Unidentified Sculpture, Studio, Box A, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Unidentified Sculpture, World's Fair San Francisco, Box A, undated; 1 Glass negatives (8 x 10) (Box 8)
    - Unidentified Sculpture, Studio, Box A, undated; 3 Glass negatives (8 x 10) (Box 8)
    - Brewster Monument, Studio, Box B, undated; 3 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Brewster Monument, On Site, Box B, undated; 4 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Anthony Ladd (Relief), Box C, undated; 4 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Constantine Johnston (Bust), Box C, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Lydia Babbitt (Sculpture), Box C, undated; 4 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Memorial Tablet, Hold Memorial Babies' Hospital, Studio, Box C, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Doherty (Bust), Box D, undated; 4 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Doherty (Sitter), Box D, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Dr. Babbott (Relief), Box D, undated; 4 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Dr. Babbott (Sitter), Box D, undated; 3 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Resor (Relief), Box D, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Davison (Relief), Box D, undated; 2 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Underwood (Bust), Box D, undated; 9 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Con Edison Plaque, Box D, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Selinger Children (Reliefs), Box D, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Leroy Wiles (Bust), Box E, undated; 2 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Stuyvesant Reredos (Relief), Box E, undated; 3 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Hathaway School Fountain, Cleveland, Studio, Box E, undated; 2 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Helen (Bust), Box F, undated; 1 Glass negatives (8 x 10) (Box 8)
    - Freda N. Brunn (Memorial Relief), Box F, undated; 1 Glass negatives (8 x 10) (Box 8)
    - "George and Harriet Davison and Their Son Robert Alfred" (Relief), Box F, undated; 1 Glass negatives (8 x 10) (Box 8)
    - Jean Olcott (Bust), Box F, undated; 1 Glass negatives (8 x 10) (Box 8)
    - Charles Perry 2nd (Headstone), Box F, undated; 1 Glass negatives (8 x 10) (Box 8)
    - Unidentified Bust, Box F, undated; 8 Glass negatives (8 x 10) (Box 8)
    - A. Lewisohn (Sitter), Box G, undated; 7 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Wm. Henry Harrison (Bust), Box H, undated; 3 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Wm. Henry Harrison (Bust), Studio, Box H, undated; 2 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Walt Whitman (Bust), Hall of Fame for Great Americans, Box J, undated; 2 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Peter Cooper (Bust), Hall of Fame for Great Americans, Box J, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Eli Whitney (?) (Bust), Hall of Fame for Great Americans, Box J, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Carl Maria von Weber (Bust), Box K, undated; 2 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - 'The Sacred Fire' Statue, Box K, undated; 1 Glass negatives (8 x 10) (Box 8)
    - Eleanor (Bust), Box K, undated; 2 Glass negatives (8 x 10) (Box 8)
    - Beata (Baby) Sculpture, Box K, undated; 1 Glass negatives (8 x 10) (Box 8)
    - Unidentified Sculpture, Studio, Box K, undated; 2 Glass negatives (9.5 x 11.75) (Box 14)
    - 'Achievement' Sculpture, Box L, undated; 1 Glass negatives (8 x 10) (Box 8)
    - Unidentified Sculpture, Box L, undated; 2 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Unidentified Sculpture, Box L, undated; 10 Glass negatives (8 x 10) (Box 8)
    - Unidentified Sculpture, Studio, Box L, undated; 4 Glass negatives (8 x 10) (Box 8)
    - Head of George Davison (Sitter), Box L, undated; 6 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - H. L. Doherty (Sitter), Box L, undated; 3 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Christian Herter (Relief/Plaque), Box M, undated; 1 Glass negatives (8 x 10) (Box 8)
    - 'Actor's Fund' (Relief), Box M, undated; 2 Glass negatives (8 x 10) (Box 8)
    - Cleveland Fountain: 'Sun,' 'Earth,' and 'Sun, Mist and Sea,' Box M, undated; 4 Glass negatives (9.5 x 11.75) (Box 14)
    - DeVinne (Bust), Box O, undated; 8 Glass negatives (8 x 10) (Box 9)
    - Unidentified Heads, Work in Memorial Studio, Box P, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Unidentified Sculpture, Work in Memorial Studio, Box P, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Unidentified Sculpture, Work in Memorial Studio, Box P, 1 Glass negatives (4.25 x 5.5) (Box 7)
    - Rosemanry Mora (Bust), Work in Memorial Studio, Box P, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Frances Ladd Sculpture, Work in Memorial Studio, Box P, undated; 2 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Swimming Boy Sculpture, Work in Memorial Studio, Box P, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Girl on Sphinx, Work in Memorial Studio, Box P, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Anne Skidmore (Bust), Work in Memorial Studio, Box P, undated; 2 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Small 'Beyond' (Ivory), Work in Memorial Studio, Box P, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Showcase with Small Bronzes, Work in Memorial Studio, Box P, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Young Girl with Tortoise (Bronze), Work in Memorial Studio, Box P, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - 'Echo of Greece' Sculpture, Work in Memorial Studio, Box P, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Robert McDonald (Relief), Work in Memorial Studio, Box P, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Unidentified Bust, Work in Memorial Studio, Box P, undated; 6 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 6)
    - Unidentified Sculpture, Work in Memorial Studio, Box P, undated; 4 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 7)
    - Constantine Johnson (Bust), Box S, undated; 7 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 7)
    - Constantine Johnson (Sculpture), Box S, undated; 2 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 7)
    - Waterfall Sculpture, Box S, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 7)
    - Charles M. Jacobs (Bust), Box S, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 7)
    - Purves Family (Relief), Box S, undated; 2 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 7)
    - 'The Awakening' (Marble), Box S, undated; 2 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 7)
    - Dawn (Head), Box S, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 7)
    - 'Vortex' (Sculpture), Box S, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 7)
    - "In As Much As You Have Done ... " (Relief), Box S, undated; 1 Glass negatives (8 x 10) (Box 9)
    - Wood Figure, Box S, undated; 1 Glass negatives (8 x 10) (Box 9)
    - Man (Sculpture), Box S, undated; 1 Glass negatives (8 x 10) (Box 9)
    - Unidentified Bust, Box S, undated; 5 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 7)
    - Unidentified Sculpture, Box S, undated; 3 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 7)
    - Unidentified Sculpture, Pan-Pacific Exposition, Box S, undated; 1 Glass negatives (8 x 10) (Box 9)
    - 'Spirit of the Woods, A Stoker,' Box 1, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 7)
    - 'Nero' (Bronze), Studio, Box 1, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 7)
    - 'Le Masque' (Bronze), Box 1, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 7)
    - Faun with Kid (Bronze), Box 1, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 7)
    - Indian Horse Group, Box 1, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 7)
    - Bacchante Head, Box 1, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 7)
    - Unidentified Sculpture, Box 1, undated; 2 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 7)
    - Unidentified Sculpture, Studio, Box 1, undated; 1 Glass negatives (4.25 x 5.5) (Box 7)
    - Unidentified Bust, Box 1, undated; 2 Glass negatives (4.25 x 5.5) (Box 7)
    - Unidentified Drawing, "1st Mention," Box 1, undated; 1 Glass negatives (4.25 x 5.5) (Box 7)
    - Unidentified Drawing, Box 1, undated; 1 Glass negatives (4.25 x 5.5) (Box 7)
    - 'Out of Work' Sculpture, Unlabelled Box, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 7)
    - Bradbury Bust, Unlabelled Box, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 7)
    - Horses, Unlabelled Box, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 7)
    - 'Big Wave' Sculpture, Unlabelled Box, undated; 1 Glass negatives (8 x 10) (Box 9)
    - Unidentified Sitter, Unlabelled Box, undated; 5 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 7)
    - Unidentified Sculpture, Unlabelled Box, undated; 1 Glass negatives (5 x 7) (Box 7)
    - Unidentified Sculpture, Unlabelled Box, 1913 February 4; 1 Glass negatives (8 x 10) (Box 9)
    - Unidentified Sculpture, Unlabelled Box, undated; 2 Glass negatives (8 x 10) (Box 9)
    - Unidentified Sculpture with Tools, Unlabelled Box, undated; 2 Glass negatives (8 x 10) (Box 9)
  - Oversized Photograph Album, Volume 1, undated; (1 volume) (Box 11)
  - Oversized Photographs of People and Places, Box 5, F 13 (Box 11)